good evening and welcome to the free
Assange vigil number 46.1 weird
46 weeks straight into this series uh my
name is Steve boy Keenan I am joined by
my co-host Andrew Smith and Kendra
Christian today marks three thousand
four hundred and fifty one days since
the illegal and arbitrary detention of
Julian Assange began 404 days and he was
trafficked out of the Ecuador and he
keyed up of units code a 4.2 billion
dollar IMF loan to Ecuador 111 days
until the second round of extradition
hearings begin in London and our
protests begin in DC one thousand eighty
one days to incarceration for our
reality winner and on the plus side
sixty seven days of freedom for Chelsea
Manning following the decades-long
WikiLeaks grand jury dismissal we are
joined tonight by the convo couches
Fiorella Isabel by the Ron Paul
Institute's Norman singleton and I
believe eventually John Kerry akka will
be on as well guys we are uh we are
organizing for DC as we speak
and as such we are trying to get our
sorry behinds there we've you haven't go
fund me up we're gonna post a link a few
times throughout the vigil tonight feel
free to share the link if you can't
donate if you can't donate please do
that
the the trial is going to last about
three weeks we are trying to make sure
that at least some of us are there for
all three of those weeks so please if
you can donate if you can't share the
link um let's go ahead and and start off
the round of interviews though um how's
goofy how you doing good see it it's you
know quarantine eating doing as many
shows as possible I'm still trying to
get as much information out there as
possible taking care of this
advantage of this time to actually be
putting out as much content and be
diving deep into what's left of the
electoral process in this country which
is a sad sad state of affairs right now
given that what is work well that's
exactly you know there's a lot of people
laughs people that need guidance but I
think it's actually an opportunity to
take things outside of electoral
politics and actually go in that
direction and stop relying on
politicians to be the sole people that
change anything right like there's a lot
of movements that we could be a part of
I couldn't agree with that more I've
been screaming at people since the mid
90s doing I could vote for the first
time the footing you're putting your
faith in politicians is the last
possible thing you would want to do and
the voting is the latest and least
effective political action anyone can
make having said that I guess there's
there's probably still down to like they
haven't canceled elections entirely yet
they're gonna try according to Greg
Palast up to 20% of the vote can be
tampered with by mail-in ballot which I
guess is a little bit better than going
and voting on an electron the Christian
yeah I'm not entirely sure about that I
don't know we are we are actually John
Kerry ah cues in the house now - John
how you doing hey folks how are you
Steve doing well it's good to see you
again sir pleasure and I'm gonna pitch
this one - I'm gonna pitch this one -
norm first and then you guys can hop in
at what point do people do people stop
paying attention to electoral politics
as the sole vehicle through which change
can happen that one's for you norm but
if he doesn't on me
then somebody else can field it hello oh
sorry about that I'm putting my dog way
okay and funny because dogs you have to
treat them like like you would treat a
dog or a toddler which is discipline and
constant watching them and not letting
them get away with anything and I think
that the question about electoral
politics I see the point that people say
it's a dead end I would say that the
problem is not so much that it's a dead
end or the people put too much faith in
politicians I would actually say that
you shouldn't put any faith in
politicians as a Christian I actually
have a Messiah and Savior named Jesus
Christ and I will i really prefer him to
Donald Trump or Joe Biden but you the
the the thing that people fail to do in
political movements enough of is holding
politicians accountable and forgetting
that the real work begins the day after
election because you really need to be
pressuring constantly the politicians to
make sure they keep their promises to
make sure they don't portray you to make
sure they don't sell you out to the
special interest and the party
leadership and not to step on anybody's
toes here but from what I've been seeing
and reading and hearing lately from a
few progressive sources particularly
Jimmy Dore is it correct pronunciation
in is that and some others is that the
left is actually doing a fairly bad job
of that much worse than the right did I
think the freedom caucus did a much
better job of trying to hold Boehner and
Ryan accountable and standing up to them
then the Progressive Caucus is doing
with Nancy Pelosi
I don't personally don't think the
possessive caucus is incentivize to hold
to any sort of progressive ideals there
the there's no accountability because
they're either going to get primary from
within the Democratic Party or they're
going to get primary by somebody else
who's going to go to Washington and run
up against the wall that is Nancy Pelosi
passing 82 to 88 percent of Donald
Trump's agenda that's Chuck Schumer
voting to fast-track what now a total of
198 judges but fast-tracking 37 of them
they're running into a machine that
incentivizes them to participate and to
ignore the electorate am i and and fees
got the fees got the pulse on this
because that's what her show cover is 99
you know what that that's what the
organization that I run and I just want
to correct briefly that my introduction
is i i'm with campaign for liberty which
is dr. ron paul's 501 C 4 grassroots
activism and education group we are
separate from the Ron Paul Institute
which is a 501 C 3 educational
foundation that focuses on foreign
policy and civil liberties although I am
a big fan and good friend of Daniel
McAdams and a fan of everything that the
Institute does but I think that what we
do at campaign for liberty as we try to
mobilize people to call email and write
their representatives on legislation I
know people can be cynical and say well
what good does one phone call do well
one phone call doesn't do actually
doesn't do any good the multiply but
multiply one by a hundred phone calls
and then you're you're you are actually
going to make an impact there's strength
in numbers there are strength and
accountability and there is strength and
backbone and ilona there's a lot of guys
so when i when i worked for dr. paul for
15 years on capitol hill from 1997 to
2012 11 of those is this legislative
director which is the top policy job at
a congressional office and i can tell
you from that we did see a chain
in how politicians were willing members
of Congress are willing to stand up and
stand with dr. Paul on issues like audit
the Fed and and even opposing the
Patriot Act and foreign interventionism
and that wasn't because all of a sudden
they had a come-to-jesus moment and
realized that Ron was right it was
because they saw that there was a
constituency out there for these ideas
that was mobilized enthusiastic and was
actually coming to their town hall
meetings calling their office writing
that their office is emailing their
offices and demanding that they stand
with Ron you know we just had a vote on
provisions of the Patriot Act being
reauthorized I believe permanently how
about go see well it went really bad I
mean there's several things there's the
HR six six six six that allows that it's
just less more privation of privacy
rights against people
then there's the resolution that was
just voted down it was an amendment to
protect the FBI from going after your
browser history and ten ten senators
didn't show up for that vote was only in
the Senate the house hasn't loaded on it
yet and one of those senators was
senator Bernie Sanders he hasn't
necessarily been the staunchest advocate
of civil liberties I feel like that is
one of his weak points from a person
from my perspective but it was important
that he was there and he didn't show up
and that that sparked a lot of criticism
because if he is to be the leader even
still right now the progressive movement
he should be protecting our civil
liberties and I I think that's a very
general assertion what did civil
liberties I mean a lot of people in on
the left and I consider myself to be
part of the left do not even care or
realize how important their civil
liberties are they see that as a
libertarian construct and they look at
it with disdain and I think that is
because some of the
you know the Republican more
conservative side of the libertarian has
kind of been against social safety nets
but I think there is a coalition there
that could be built upon by certain
candidates I think Jesse Ventura was
would be a great candidate that kind of
gets from both ends he gets from the
left he also gets from the more
independent minded libertarian saucy
Gabbard was able to do the same while
she was campaigning for the presidency
but I think what we're seeing here is
fascism of the left and the fascism of
the right are entirely tools of the
establishment the left the liberal left
I would say loves to call out the the
right as be fascist let's just say
Donald Trump is a fascist but they fail
to realize is both Democrats and
Republicans are consistently getting rid
of a BS corpus they're completely
diminishing the power that we have the
individual freedoms that we have as
people and they use the idea the facade
of national security and safety to do
that we're seeing that happen right now
because there's a pandemic and they can
easily use that excuse to infringe upon
our civil liberties and that's a very
dangerous thing that's happening and I
think it's something that more people on
the left on the Socialist Left need to
sort of pay attention to because I'm not
really seeing it I'm seeing it more on
on the independent libertarian side and
I think there's something to be said
about that and something to explore for
whoever next that we support as either
President Congress whatever they should
be talking about your civil liberties
they should be talking about the
election integrity they should be
talking about the issues that nobody's
talking about right now the fact that
our system is set up to make your vote
not count it is it is it is jumping
through hoops to simply cast a vote
Americans are very lazy when it comes to
participation in our political system
also because of the fact that this is
how the system makes it it makes you
it's better for the the establishment
that you don't pay attention that you're
overworked
so yeah so John um as someone that's
personally experienced the power of the
national security state and someone
that's involved in traditional media
structure um what do you think are some
good ways that we could try to coalesce
people into like a post partisan
dialogue about civil liberties like free
speech about privacy and and things like
that good question
tough question I was thinking a minute
ago that you know we've we've got to
push some of these leaders on the left
and the right people like Bernie Sanders
because Ron Wyden is not gonna be around
forever and we can't put all of our eggs
in the baskets of Ron Wyden and Mike Lee
and and Rand Paul it's just not gonna
get us anywhere so with that said you
know I feel like like the alternative
media is gaining a foothold that I've
never seen before
I for one get my news from the likes of
consortium news and reader supported
news and and outlets like that I scan
outlets on the left and the right and
and I've gotten to the point where I
rarely go to the mainstream media I
think I'm not alone in that I think that
that's a trend and I think that that's
where we we need to go with that said
what we lack most importantly is money
we you know let me tell you a short
story in 2016 I traveled to twelve
states with Gary Johnson who was the
libertarian nominee for president that
year and one of the things he told me
and he mentioned it very off handedly
that really stuck with me was that the
Libertarian Party does not have a
benefactor there was a family in
California that made its money in canned
tomatoes he said that had been very
generous but in terms of an actual
ongoing benefactor there just wasn't one
the Democrats and the Republicans have
hundreds of such benefactors well it's
the same thing with the alternative
media we need a benefactor
whether that media is on the left or the
right because it's one thing to write
for these outlets it's another thing for
the news to actually get out there for
people to actually see it I feel like I
right my fingers to the bone right I
write op-eds at least every week I try
to pump out books as frequently as I can
and that's not unusual there are a lot
of people that do that but if nobody has
access to the to the sites nobody's
gonna nobody's gonna get the news
nobody's gonna be informed the way we
think people ought to be informed and I
think that one of the things we need to
do is to find ourselves one or two or 50
of these benefactors certainly we're not
the the only people in America thinking
this way um I have a question kind of
for all the guests I mean given with
what we've discussed then exactly you
know how important you know if you could
convey to people is it that we free
Julian Assange you know that we that we
work for this Free Press to get that out
I mean and this is for all the guests to
I think it's very important because the
president here is chilling in terms of
its effect on free speech and people who
want to publish before he became the
great defender civil liberties when the
president a president his own party with
the target of the deep state but he'd
never really expressed that much
concerned with overreach and massive
government surveillance but it was just
anti-war activists and even anti-tax Tea
Party activists that were being targeted
by the deep state yeah I mean I agree
with that I mean I think it's important
that we set a precedent for alternative
media because mainstream media is a
propaganda machine now for the further
military-industrial complex and for the
intelligence community they control what
everybody the majority of the population
in our country sees hears and believes
and no matter how hard we try we are at
a disadvantage in money and networking
and reach as independent media and so
when there is such misinformation and
propaganda and mis-education of people
you're going to get a population that
doesn't see that they're walking right
into the slaughter and that's where
we're at and we're slowly creeping up as
independent media the only issue I have
with like well let me just first say a
Julian Assange whoever is the President
or whoever we start putting our support
bike needs to be Pro protecting
whistleblowers and they absolutely 100%
need to be because our freedom of speech
is one of the most important things that
we have as a society and it's one of the
things that America is always valued
itself I have a freedom of speech of
saying things you might disagree with
this is why I've always been against
censorship even if it came from somebody
like Alex Jones it
like once they started doing that they
started going after everybody and so we
need to be very like proactive in how we
are going to handle that because right
now they're just gonna label people as
Russian assets etc and I think whoever
else we support for any sort of politics
has to be have that in the front of
their mind they have to be protecting
our truth tellers and that's that's what
has to be pushed I don't see that being
pushed on the left as much as it should
be
I think you know this last election kind
of is showing that but even people like
Tulsi Gabbard and other progressives are
not really like when it comes to like
civil liberties they like you know
they'll say oh we have to protect people
first and that's kind of something that
I'm wary of when it comes to politicians
they're just not really on it and I
think it'll come from independent media
like you guys and us and you know
because it is our livelihood - it's our
lives that depend on standing up for
people like Julian Assange and other
whistleblowers
there you go ahead Andrew no I was just
gonna I was just gonna ask John if you
wanted oh yeah I actually would this is
something I've been trying to talk about
a lot in the the last several weeks one
of the things that just flabbergast Smee
is our seeming inability to convince the
likes of The Washington Post and The New
York Times and other mainstream outlets
that if Julian is convicted they're next
you know they think that well Donald
Trump's not going to be around forever
he might not even be around for more
than another eight months but we saw
under the Obama administration
mainstream journalists described as
unindicted co-conspirators by the
Attorney General of the United States
we saw raids on the homes of working
mainstream journalists if they refused
to stand up and admit publicly that
Julian Assange is a journalist
to any publisher there's literally
nothing to stop the government from
targeting them next it's as simple as
that and that's to that that's what the
special administrative measures within
the United States really reveal is the
true power that the federal government
holds that it can push down against any
individual that it chooses because
that's something that they basically
said yes Julian will be placed under
special administrative measures when he
gets here which basically completely
limits access to his attorney access to
information and a bunch of other just
heinous things across the board
including 23 hours a day if not more of
solitary confinement could you talk a
little bit more or do you kind of have a
perspective on ways in general that we
can push back against projects or not
projects but policies like Sam's and
other criminal and justices that happen
inside of our justice system there are
so many different organizations doing
great work out there I work very closely
for example with the human rights
defense which also publishes prison
legal news and criminal legal news
magazines so there are a lot of us out
there working kind of independently of
one another if we if we can figure out a
way to work together and to harness the
power that we have I think will be far
more impactful
right now we're generally ignored by the
mainstream media but I mean everything
from these events like the one we're
doing right now which I find to be very
beneficial and I'm I'm always surprised
at how many people watch these and go to
them later on YouTube it's very
heartening but we need to find a way to
work together in a more integrated
fashion so that we can get the word out
and that we don't look like you know
just some guy or some woman standing off
to the side outside of Julian's trial
yelling about civil liberties we have
important things to say and you know
people who have who have legitimate
experiences that the media
to focus on their they're on point
with Julian and I think I think we've
got a story to tell
I think that there is some room for
optimism the fact that there is an
alternative media today the fact that
there are organizations like campaign
for they're pretty like the Ron Paul
Institute on the libertarian side the
fact that dr. Paul is a daily program
that is doing quite well telling some of
the truth about the braun virus and how
crazy it is we basically shut down the
entire economy for a virus that you
probably have a less than 1% chance of
dying unless you have a pre-existing
condition but and also going back to
something we talked about before this
what happened last week in the Senate we
came within one boat of getting put into
law that you have to get a warrant now
silly me I thought that there was this
thing called the Fourth Amendment that
already put a warrant requirement in the
lobby for the government could take your
your seizure papers and records but I
guess that went out that actually went
out with the war on drugs back in the
80s and 90s under especially under
George the first Attorney General
William bar that name may ring a bell
with some of you but anyway that was
actually when you consider where we were
just ten years ago what on this bill
that the first indication that he wasn't
gonna be nearly as good on foreign
policy and civil liberties as president
as he was on the campaign trail voted
for the FISA bill in Oh 8 and it was
made clean widely acknowledged that this
was just a political move on his part
because he didn't think he could vote
against it where today you see people on
both sides lining up to vote for a wide
Danes amendment you have a very liberal
senator and you have a very conservative
Senator libertarian is senator coming
together to stop warrantless wiretapping
and they almost won even though
McConnell set a 60-vote threshold this
is progress
some other things were making progress
on foreign policy on the Republican
Party Donald Trump did what Ron Paul
tried to do and back in the 90s Pat
Buchanan tried to do which is run a
successful campaign in the Republican
primary challenging conventional
neoconservative wisdom and running as
the avowed enemy of Bill Kristol
and dr. Paul did better than anyone
could could have expected his son is not
better than anyone could have expected
in his career but then also look at
Donald Trump in 2016 he stood up before
a Republican primary debate and said
that going into Iraq was a horrible
mistake and he actually thought there is
a groundswell of support of questioning
of foreign policy of civil liberties and
of the Federal Reserve which ought to be
something that libertarians and
progressives can join together on
because the Federal Reserve is as Daniel
McAdams once brilliantly called it the
dark heart of the welfare warfare state
we can argue about the welfare state but
let's let's work together on getting rid
of the world warfare state and let's at
least get rid of the corporate welfare
state I think it's about time that one
thing that kind of annoys me about
Republicans is when the farm bill comes
up every four or five years Republicans
get up and stand up and scream about we
need to get single mothers off the dole
so we need to put work requirements for
the EBT program and then they'll shovel
built several of billions of subsidies
to millionaire farmers most of them
don't even have their even walked on on
a real farm and there's something that I
think there's there should be room for
convergence on the left-right
convergence on libertarian and
progressive conserve convergence on in
some let's at least get rid of the
welfare for the rich and then we can
talk about what's it what what
provisions the society could make for
the poor and if I could just be engaged
I apologize for rambling but I have a
lot of these these topics excite me as
you might might be able to tell somebody
said libertarians are against the social
safety net that's actually not true
libertarians are against at least a
federal government provided social
safety net for a variety of reasons one
of which is that send out checks to
people without a screwing it up and be
making sure that the big guys the fat
cats are taken care of and the little
and the average person gets some prompts
and it's supposed to be great no that's
it that's a good point I've said forever
that I support the idea of a universal
health care system I just don't want
Congress running it i Andrew makes the
point that like if the National Nurses
Union was in charge of universal health
care that would put us in a much better
position than say you know Chuck Schumer
and Mitch McConnell even in this
situation right now pollen tier is in
charge of our health care yeah yeah and
we've got Palantir in charge running
running the health care of you know
partnered up with the NHS in the UK as
well and when Peter Thiel is running the
show the only person that wins or the
only entity that wins is an
ever-increasing surveillance state when
I pause dramatically like that that
someone's queue to hop in John you've
been on before so one of the big things
go ahead be I'm sorry oh no I was just
gonna say you know like I I think people
don't care who runs it as long as it
happens
other countries have a not necessarily
been a cure for all but a nationalized
type of health care system and they are
able to manage it accordingly I don't
think it's a matter of Congress being
unable to it's a matter of Congress not
wanting to because the money and the
lobbyists are there I I don't
necessarily trust the government to run
it but I think if we were to point the
right people to run a health care system
where there was no middleman or you
could just have basic health care the
choice to do that if you'd if you'd like
but I think I think it's important that
we the argument that the government is
going to infringe they're doing it right
now when we have a private health
insurance industry there they're doing
it right now
that doesn't matter I don't think it's
going to hurt us go towards a universal
health care system we just have to find
what works for our country because our
states we're obviously a different
country than like say Denmark and it's
gonna take a sort of different process
for it well one thing to keep in mind
about the Affordable Health Care Act or
Obamacare
widely known is that my friends MP party
at the Washington great work and
regulatory state has pointed out that
while Obama was out in the Rose Garden
demonizing the insurance industry for
fighting against his health care plan
insurance industry lobbyists were
sitting back in the West Wing with Obama
staffers writing the bill and when
people say oh big insurance was against
Obama care I say right because big
businesses would naturally hate a law
that says that it is a crime for you to
fail to purchase my product so this is
something a parallel to that that we're
seeing in Julian's case
when they were in court early on here
after you'd been taken into Belmarsh the
the judge who's supposed to be this
neutral arbiter of this globally
impacting press freedom case walks to
the back of the room to meet with the
americans that are there so it's this
level of corruption whether it exists in
like a corporate state or within the
larger institutions of the I would say
Allah privatized police state at this
point but John if you could because you
have the most experience in handling
these kinds of situations firsthand and
like litigation against the government
and being prosecuted for proliferating
truth could you talk a little bit about
what Julian actually faces I know we've
gone over it before but just to kind of
lay it out again sure sure
Julian faces a very tough experience in
the Eastern District of Virginia and
frankly much of that is just because
he's headed to the Eastern District of
Virginia I've told this story before but
I think it bears repeating in the
Eastern District here in Alexandria
Virginia is known as the espionage court
because that's where the government
likes to file most of its it's national
security charges I was charged here
Julian's charged here ed Snowden's
charged here Jeffrey sterling was
charged here and no national security
defendant has ever won a case in the
Eastern District
now I predicted for a long time wrongly
as it turned out that Julian's judge
would be judge Leonie brinkema who
usually reserves these national security
cases for herself it turned out that
brinkema had the case taken away from
her by the chief judge who just happens
to have been a FISA Court judge before
he was named to the Eastern District
that makes me want to run screaming from
the room we also know that that the
government intends to invoke something
called CIPA the control the
the classified information Protection
Act what they're gonna do is they're
going to clear the courtroom they're
going to cover the windows and the doors
with plastic sheeting and duct tape so
no one can can aim a laser beam at the
windows and pick up the vibrations and
hear what classified conversations are
taking place inside the courtroom
everyone will be dismissed except the
prosecutors and Julian the I'm sorry the
prosecutors the defense attorneys and
Julian the clerk and the bailiff and the
jury and that's it nobody else will be
allowed in the room furthermore the
judge is going to issue a list of words
to the jury that will replace words that
the prosecution alleges are classified
so let's say the word NSA is class or
the acronym NSA is classified maybe
they'll call it zebra or swimming pool
so anytime someone needs to refer to NSA
they won't say NSA they'll say zebra and
there's gonna be a little paper that the
jury has and it'll say NSA equals zebras
so they can follow along and understand
what the heck is being said in the
courtroom it's a ridiculous exercise and
frankly I've always maintained that it
serves to bias the jury against the
defendant because the implication is
even these Intervale individual words
are so highly classified that we can't
even utter them in this closed courtroom
so he must be guilty he must be a bad
guy he must have done all these terrible
wrong things so we have to convict him
uh with that said no let me add one more
thing from my own experience and again
I've told the story before but it bears
repeating when I was headed to trial I
hired Oh J Simpson's jury consultant he
was the is the the father of my best
friend's wife and so he
did it for free the man's never lost a
case he represented George Zimmerman in
the Trayvon Martin shooting he
represented
besides OJ William Kennedy Smith in his
rape case the guy's never lost a case
literally he's never lost a case and so
he came up to Washington he lives in
Dallas and we got him a security
clearance from the Justice Department
and he went through the files my files
15,000 pages of discovery and when it
was all over we sat in the knot when it
was over when he had finished going
through the files we sat in my
attorney's conference room and he said
look here's the bottom line if we were
in any other district in America I would
say let's go for it we're gonna win this
thing
but the Eastern District of Virginia he
said you don't have a chance he said
your jury is going to be made up of
employees or family members of employees
of the CIA the Pentagon the Department
of Homeland Security the FBI
intelligence community contractors he
said you don't have a chance it's all
stacked against you that's why they
charged you here in the first place he
said my advice to you is to take the
deal and I took the deal well Julian's
not likely to be offered a deal the the
whole point of Julian's case is to make
an example of him because this case is
far bigger than just Julian Assange this
case is about media and media freedom
and so long as the mainstream media
decides that Julian is somehow their
enemy and doesn't come out in their
editorial pages every single day day
after day to support him
IIIi think that a very bad precedents
gonna be said said here now I've said in
the past that I think the one chance he
has in the Eastern District is is the
chance of jury nullification there has
to be one right thinking person out
there you know out of what's a jury 12
people at the federal level nine people
12 people I don't know I never made it
to a jury but there's got to be one
person out there who can think
independently and
and conclude that this is just wrong
this whole prosecution is wrong the case
is wrong
the man has already suffered and it has
to end that's not much to hang your hat
on but I struggle every day thinking
what we can do to make it better and I'm
not coming up with a lot of ideas I mean
not that kind of inspires me to
something that Adam Koch Ash had talked
about and one of our previous vigils I
think where it was the way that people
choose to educate other people about
certain issues and how there's not any
group using jury nullification as a
standing point for their health project
to the world um do you think that
starting some kind of educational
campaign in the Eastern District of
Virginia about jury nullification ah
would be effective do you find that what
I do I do indeed and you know I've
raised this with a number of attorney
friends who said that I was crazy that
jury nullification is is illegal that
you can't encourage jury nullification I
said I'm an independent citizen I'm not
an attorney standing up in court and
saying jury nullification right I'm
allowed to have an opinion and I think
that there's a role for jury
nullification look you know at one time
it was legal for six-year-olds to work
in the mines now it's not sometimes laws
are just bad laws the Espionage Act is
one of them so I think that there is a
role for jury nullification is that
right like by going around the Foggy
Bottom strip malls putting copies of the
nose Melser interview under people's
windshield that I'll go do that there
used to be a group called the fully
informed jury Association feature I'm
not sure or if they're still around or
how active they are but they used but
one of their projects was having people
stand outside the courthouse and hand
out flyers targeting potential jurors
informing them of their right to judge
on the facts of the law so it has been
done I think the the
carrion party at one point was very much
behind this effort as well I kind of I
kind of like to get your reaction norm
to to John's John story and the
knowledge that he dropped in it was
stuff that you were already aware of
having worked in DC and been a part of
that order uh well I actually think I
heard John discuss this the the problem
of the Eastern District of Virginia on
Sputnik radio one day and now I just
outed myself as clearly I'm a Russian
agent but but I wasn't I was not aware
of the Eastern District problem and I
don't think a lot of people are aware
are aware of that but everything he said
makes sense and it certainly makes sense
in terms of the jury pool that you're
going to be looking for you're going to
be drawing because of the nature of it
from people who are government
contractors people with the Pentagon and
they're in that culture that they
believe that they are in the right that
they are protecting America and the
people like Julian Assange Chelsea
Manning Edward snowed and John are bad
people who are disloyal to the greatest
country and the history of the world I
have a question for Fiorella I'm
wondering what what do you hit the most
is like roadblocks for civil liberties
and for you know like this situation
Julian Assange within the left like what
are some of the biggest roadblocks that
you see there because like just even
from what we were talking about you know
we're looking at basically you know a
secret court not being able to know
what's going on I mean for the public to
me this is also really bad for our civil
liberties not to know what's going on in
the biggest you know Free Press case of
our lifetime yeah I mean I think the
biggest roadblock is the fact that
progressives especially though like
progressives who consider themselves
ultra leftist do not consider this a big
issue well it's definitely not one of
their main concerns and it's something
that it should be a main concern but
like what I see with people I know on
the left they really like this is
probably less on their list and because
they look at immediate concerns they're
looking at the immediacy of a health
care system failing they're looking at
the immediacy of being unable to pay
right they're looking at all these
issues and in an in a sense it's it's
sort of a catch-22 because those two
things work against each other you guys
know pasta pasta is he was a Tulsi
supporter primarily because he supported
civil liberties and foreign policy above
everything else my belief is that we
should support both of them but at the
same time it's like you're not in my
opinion it's really hard to get people
to tension to something like Julian
Assange if they can't see the immediate
concern so like if people are too busy
like working you know for jobs and they
can't pay their bills they're really not
gonna care about people being bombed
abroad in different countries just as
much as they're really not gonna care
about what happens to one guy they're
not looking at the bigger picture as -
wow this has so much of a precedent and
it's so much affect so it's going to
affect us for years and years and years
because we're not paying attention to
the biggest case regarding freedom of
speech in our lifetime and it's really
hard I think there has to be like
working in tandem we have to address
like the concerns a lot of the working
people have while being like look people
aren't gonna hear your concerns the
government is free to do whatever they
want and abuse you because we don't have
real like journalism in America we we
have the Fourth Estate was supposed to
be like for the people it was supposed
to be the fourth branch of government
and right now it's just a propaganda
machine for the military and the
intelligence community and so if we can
make people realize that they're not
going to get all of these domestic
issues and these concerns if they don't
also pay attention
to foreign policy and the civil
liberties that are being constantly
infringed upon us on the daily then we
could probably make that connection you
know what I mean they have to make that
connection they're not listening to you
when you're talking about Julian Assange
because they're looking at it as like
okay well that's him that's a separate
case no it's all connected and we have
to look and kind of highlight exactly
why everything is connected something
I've found to be effective at least on a
person-to-person basis and then through
through my show that I really don't hear
a lot in media in general is that your
cause is [__] dead without the
ability to access free and free and open
information you're maybe whatever
whatever it is you're into whatever is
on the front of your sign if it doesn't
have free Julian Assange on the back of
it you're doing you're organizing wrong
because if we don't have the ability to
get this information out there
regardless of what it is it's dead it
goes nowhere you're talking to the three
people that you know about it they'd
already know about it
well look I would say look at the Ron
Paul campaigns of o8 2012
particularly Inouye when it started it
was a very very took advantage of Meetup
of Facebook and MySpace but anybody
remembers MySpace and YouTube and all of
those platforms that were at the time
much more open to dissonant ideas and
organized shared videos shared articles
by dr. Paul and got the word out there
as an IDE on what grassroots can
accomplish unfortunately today you have
these big tech companies in bed with the
national security state and we see the D
platforming going on the censorship for
the constant problems with YouTube deep
D monetizing certain voices but it's
still but we still have this ability we
can still find alternatives we can still
get the word out to people and again you
can always go
back to your representative who is under
our constitutional system there's a
reason why there are more
representatives that there are
presidents and Senators so there's a
reason why they're up for election every
two years as opposed to every six or
every four that's because they're
supposed to be closest to to us and the
Senators are supposed to be second in
terms of being responsive to the people
and I think that it's a problem with
political activists across the board
that they kind of focus upon what the
executive is doing and they ignore the
fact that in our constitutional system
the president is not supposed to be the
king the president is supposed to be
actually accountable to the executive
branch when they wrote the Constitution
they knew what they knew they numbered
the branches one legislative two
executive three judiciary for a reason
and I think we've forgotten that and I
think that is one reason why we are
losing our liberties to amount with the
executive state and the only argument
seems to be right now is which grumpy
old man is fit to have this incredible
power of Donald Trump or Joe Biden and I
think to um in the activist communities
there's a lot or there's a lot of talk
about censorship where you have the left
pointing out the censorship on the left
and you have the right pointing out the
censorship on the right but it's hard to
find people on either side that are
willing to say both our sensors and
there are some that do and you guys are
a combo couch do a great job of this I'm
pointing out just the [__] and the
hypocrisy that exists means if you
dynamics going back to the idea of
building like a post ideological
conversation like building people up
around issues that are fundamental I
think censorship and the fight for a
free and open Internet is one of those
really big things um could you talk
about that a little bit feet about like
experiences you guys have had with
Internet censorship that you know maybe
from a big flat
or maybe one of those like coincidences
that something happened when it did oh
yeah absolutely I mean we're being
censored left and right all of our
videos that deal with anything regarding
intelligence agencies anything regarding
military industrial complex any mention
of Syria any mention of any sort of
foreign policy issue but as whele all of
that gets entirely censored I it's also
not as popular like whenever we were
talking about election integrity it is a
kind of a wonky subject so a lot of
people like it's hard to like get them
to tune in but that's some of the things
that we've experienced are like are like
being scrubbed off people being on -
described our video our technology just
seeming not to work at certain times and
I and I know that this happens because
YouTube is owned by Google so like I
know that they have their preferences we
also notice my friend Nico
notice how like they were like if you
were going to find one of his videos if
he searched it using this one program he
did it said it should be one of the top
videos but in reality on YouTube it
doesn't appear you have to search every
single word for our videos to appear so
it's the suppression is real and it's
actually known that this is the thing
that they can legally do so that's why
we're trying to look at alternative like
video sites like Rocklin that are more
people like you know people friendly
they're more like a co-op type of model
where you still can make money off of it
but you're not putting your viewers
through so much stress and they're not
subjected to ads and it's a little bit
different and I think we need to find
alternatives in media and and to kind of
take away from YouTube and I think
YouTube's time is definitely ending but
I definitely see a lot of the you know
the censorship also like in LA we we
only have two providers we have either
spectrum which bought Time Warner or we
have DirecTV which is another
corporation
I think the majority of people use
spectrum and in some parts they have a
TMT which is also another another thing
that we reuse as well and that's it you
don't have access to internet from a
different location and if your area is
not Beverly Hills Beverly Hills for
instance has fiber optic internet they
have the fastest internet and the city
of Beverly Hills can have that because
they're rich and they put all their
resources there whereas where I live in
Pasadena it's it's not the poorest but
it's also not the richest and so you
know we were robbed Picone myself pasta
we all went to City Council meeting to
push for just municipal Internet and
basically the AT&T lobbyist was there
telling the City Council to that this
just wouldn't work and they made up a
reason as to why it wouldn't work but
obviously it was money involved and we
have to find ways creative ways and
there's new technology coming up of
creating our own networks creating our
own ability to promote independent media
I don't like the idea of somebody
mentioned like just one provider I don't
like that idea because I'm against
centralized government I think a
centralized structure and anything could
be capitulate could be co-opted into a
powerful powerful person having too much
power whether like I TYT is an example
of that they started out progressives
quote-unquote and then they slowly you
know started getting these people on
their board that were venture
capitalists and had other interests and
you saw the reporting change a way to
avoid that is to have a decentralized
structure and in whatever sort of
co-opting media can form and I think
obviously it's gonna require people
putting in money to it but it's it
should be in a way that is very
transparent that doesn't mimic the way
the establishment is so I want to thank
our guests for joining us on we do have
to move to our news segment but if you
could I'll start with norm
could you let people know where to find
you your work and organization your
campaign Liberty campaign for liberty
calm
it is a 501c4 grassroots lobbying
organization our major issues are audit
the Fed repeal the Patriot Act
free-market health care that lets
doctors and patients not government
bureaucrats or insurance agencies
control the near health care and
basically just the entire Bill of Rights
from the first all the way up through
the through through the tenth we were
founded by dr. Ron Paul I really
appreciate being being on here and
everybody's time and I hope everyone
stays involved in whatever way you feel
you can best contribute to the important
cause of protecting our liberties thank
you thank you very much again and where
people can find you and the wonderful
work you do yeah thank you guys for
doing this a lot of people aren't really
covering Julius Julian Assange as much
and I always get all my news from all of
you guys so thank you for doing this and
sticking with it I will help out and
promote you guys forever I can my name
is Fiorella Isabel I have a Twitter
Fiorella underscore I am the channel we
have is the convo couch spelled just
like convo conversation and couch
and you can find us on YouTube on Roxon
we also have a facebook Instagram and
Twitter
so thank you guys so much appreciate you
thank you don't bother we said hey so do
you want to you want to run news in
order that it is on the dock there yeah
I think okay if you could grab that
Guardian article we can go into it
Mike Pompeo
okay and y'all got by now by now
hopefully you know that if there's an
opportunity to kick your own Mike Pompeo
I'm going to jump up and and take it
this is pretty this is a case where Mike
Pompeo is doing the kicking although
we'll get into why it it may backfire
the Trump administration has fired the
State Department's inspector general he
was reported to have been investigating
Secretary of State Mike Pompeo for
potential abuse of office the Inspector
General Steve linic was given notice of
his dismissal late on Friday night and
has expended Jesus and is to be replaced
by Steven ackard a close ally of the
vice president mice mike pence from his
home state of Indiana mine is a funny
little sidebar here not funny because
it's Mike Pence and the guy is really
like as funny as a bus full of dead
babies but but funny in that I grew up
in the district what my parents have
wound up representing now this is not my
fault because I was already gone but
Mike pants used to be a radio guy and
his tagline for his radio show was that
he was like Rush Limbaugh on decaf and
that was enough for the people of the
6th congressional district to beat of
Indiana to be like that's our guy
we'll take that guy um back to the
article a State Department spokesman
said that a Kurd who had been running
the office for foreign missions would
take over immediately as acting IG
according to a Democratic congressional
aide just before his abrupt dismissal
Linna could open an investigation into
allegations that Pompeo had been using a
political appointee at state to run
personal errands for him and his wife
Susan let's pause for a moment just to
recognize how perfect it is that mrs.
Pompeo is a Susan movie now go ahead
Andrew you know I just want to just take
a moment to reflect on the fact that
Mike Pompeo has a politically
politically appointed personal assistant
but like someone had to make that
decision like yep this dude
your personal assistant Mike Pompeo I
just find that I just find that
absolutely ridiculous
yeah and the you would yeah so under US
law the president is required to give 30
days notice before firing an inspector
general to allow Congress to investigate
the reasons for dismissal in recent
months Congress has not used that
month-long notice period to prevent the
termination of other watchdog officials
fired by the president linic is the
latest in a string of officials in
watchdog roles fired by the president in
recent months turning on its head the
tradition that some such jobs are filled
with non partisan figures Trump has
demanded personal loyalty from officials
working in the administration especially
those in an oversight role linic is not
the first Inspector General to be fired
late on a Friday night on April 3rd this
year Trump dismissed intelligence
community Inspector General Michael
Atkinson who had first deemed credible a
whistleblower complaint expressing
concern about Trump's call last summer
to his Ukrainian counterpart Vladimir
szalinski which ultimately triggered
impeachment proceedings against the
press president can we talk about this
for a minute because this is absolute
like hot steaming [__] on a freaking
cold pasture Lord yeah
I wanted to pause here because I don't
inherently disagree with the fact that
that other guy was fired the dude that
was spreading the [__] about the
yeah Jason burr miss was a whistleblower
who should have all these protections
and it allowed people to see the
connection between the state censorship
apparatus and the global media platforms
because if you said the person's name
Jason or Eric Eric caramello bar your
video gets me and I still can't say the
guys name so I'm stealing Jason
Bernice's little tagline for him um so I
think that's always super important to
say when impeachment comes up is that
it was [__] and it was used as a way
to exercise an enforcement of technology
at the behest of the government to
remove particular content from the
internet in a very aggressive fashion
well that and then also I don't know
what you guys think about this but with
all the things to investigate Pompeo for
you know like this is what we're
settling on this is what the Oversight
Committee is interested in this is just
when however you pronounce his last name
lenok he was basically an investigator
all the way through his career but
during his tenure at the Department of
Justice he supervised and participated
in white-collar criminal fraud cases
involving corruption and contract fraud
against the US and Iraq and Afghanistan
and just as as we know through the
Washington Post release of the Afghan
papers in late 2019 which did 100% uh
codify and just validate everything that
WikiLeaks had put out nearly a decade
earlier Afghanistan and Iraq is based on
drift like that's what what keeps us
there that's why we went in the first
place it's one of the biggest
transnational rod scams in history and
and to give him credit
David McBride is facing 50 years in
prison right now for exposing that grift
in Australia he released documents and I
don't a lot of people remember some
people never heard but the ABC News the
Australian Broadcasting Centre was rated
to have these documents seized and
removed by Australian Federal Police
because Australia doesn't have a First
Amendment protection so the federal
police are allowed to just completely
charge in ultra news records and take
documents directly from journalists and
it was David McBride's release of
information that showed the bullets
nation of the Iraq war or of the
Afghanistan war that caused those rates
to happen if we could circle back real
quick though to the not a whistleblower
or whistleblower and the Ukraine thing
we just found out today that there's
tape of Joe Biden bribing the freaking
prosecute cranium prosecutor to drop the
buries McKay's and his son holding a big
s it's not holding a billion dollars
over his head and it's on tape and Joey
[__] be goes no he doesn't come out
and say I'm bribing you but he's like
you understand what this is for a you
know in it's gone [__] day and like
imagine just imagine for a second the
Donald Trump was calling on a hot mic
going now I'm not bribing you but here's
a bag of cash and I'm pretty sure you
know what to do with it right like can
you imagine the field day the every
single one of those bedwetting NPR
liberals would have over this way and
there's crickets in mainstream media
about this about this tape crickets this
further proves that they're not a
whistleblower whistleblower isn't a
whistleblower but in fact was a guy
following orders from the CIA the last
time that we had John Kerry ocula on
this show in fact he was John was the
one who was like look there's only two
reasons that you become the CIA liaison
to the White House and it's because you
are a wide-eyed go-getter very early on
in his career or you're Erika calimero
Geller caramello bar who is a a someone
who's on his way to another position and
earned the right to a two-year soft
detail at the White House well not to
mention that I think - I mean when you
go into the Ukraine thing I mean
obviously even the
fact that they went to impeach Trump
over Ukraine showed even then not that
most people didn't know that Russia Gate
was complete nonsense and now we have
that proven even more and yet people
still don't know about it and I think
that's part of what happens here with
with Trump and not whole you know fake
news and everything like that to really
get through a different policy that has
nothing to do with the elected president
let me tell you what happened so in 2016
the Chicago Cubs broke their curse and
they won the World Series first time in
like 108 years or something like that
and after that Russia Gate broke and
people were like well [__] it the Cubs
won beating a dead horse is now
America's favorite pastime we're so gay
and we can do that forever and ever and
ever and ever and ever
long may it wave that's I and if
somebody has a better actually how many
goddamn years
well the funniest part and this is
before I get back in because I want to
read from sledder to Pelosi but the
funniest part about the Russia gate
thing is that the the anti-communist
boomers don't believe Russia gate that's
the part that cracks me up like the pro
Trump boomer generation that was raised
during the height of the Red Scare don't
believe the pro-russian propaganda yeah
free love [__] hippies are like I'm
bringing in new McCarthyism baby we live
in a cartoon it's leaderless paradox
like I think I want to say his name's
Robert Reich released a video talking
about how literally talking about the
history of how McCarthy used the Red
Scare as a way to gain power to justify
the Red Scare that they were putting on
with Russia gate so it was just like the
whole like complex of like the anti
Russia anti-communists not supporting
the anti Russia campaign was just that
blew my mind but I do so this
representative
linic rohtul
or President Trump I'm sorry I wrote a
letter to me and CEO Pelosi about linic
getting fired and I just want to read it
in its full context
it says dear Speaker Pelosi this is to
arrive as I am exercising my power as
president to remove from office the
Inspector General of the Department of
State effective 30 days from today it is
extremely important that we promote the
economy efficiency and effectiveness of
federal programs and activities the
inspector general the inspectors general
have a critical role in the achievement
of these goals as is the case with
regards to other positions where I the
president have the power to appoint by
and with the advice and consent of the
Senate it is vital that I have the
fullest confidence in the appointees
serving as inspector general it is no
longer the case with regard to this
Inspector General at a later date I will
submit to the Senate my nomination of an
individual for this position who has my
fullest confidence to meet the
appropriate qualifications so not really
much to be said there it's not like a
groundbreaking thing but I just wanted
to make sure that got put in that
because those were the official words of
trunka Pelosi in regards to that I
suppose if you're the President of the
United States and you're never going to
be anything more than the public
relations space for the oligarchy
because that's all a president is then
you would want to remind I guess your
subordinates that you're the president
all the time because Trump always finds
a way to work that in like oh and by the
way I'm the president so I get it to
this like not only do I get two scoops
of ice cream every day but I get to fire
inspectors generals and sometimes they
let me sit in the truck and let me on
the Lord like internship job that's my
point that's what I'm trying to get at
we want to go to the consortium news
article now
absolutely you want to take this one
Kendra yeah sure do you want I'll just
start at the beginning
um-hmm Scandinavian activist group has
open signatures for an appeal to the
Swedish government for a full and
transparent investigation into a
possible disappearance of documents and
the illegal destruction of evidence in
the Swedish prosecutors and police probe
of sexual allegations against Julian
Assange the appeal also demands a
Sandra's release from Belmarsh prison in
London where he is on remand an
extradition request by the United States
on espionage charges for unauthorized
possession and dissemination of
classified material it calls on Sweden
to provide him Asylum the investigation
the appeal seeks would also look into
why Assange as case appears to have
exceeded a statute of limitations as
well as into pressure British
authorities brought to bear on a Swedish
prosecutor against Assange Sweden has
three times dropped the case against the
imprisoned WikiLeaks publisher the
appeal acts on the findings of Nils
Meltzer the United Nations Special
Rapporteur on torture and other cruel
inhuman or degrading treatment who said
Swedish police forged evidence in the
case against Assange do you want me to
go into the history or read onto the
case what do you guys think if we could
I would say skip down to the actual text
itself at the bottom okay
oh just oh I was just gonna say for
anybody who hasn't seen this article yet
it's a really great one it's another one
of those good articles to share with
people too because they may give a great
breakdown of the Swedish case which I
know what most people are familiar with
but especially someone who might not
know it's a good it's a good quick break
found at that so the text of the appeal
set Julian Assange free appeal to the
Swedish government the whistleblower
website WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange
is detained in the British high-security
prison Belmarsh his health is in a
critical condition
we the signatories of this appeal fear
for his life and mental health do the
treatment he is exposed to we demand his
immediate release respect for his
fundamental human rights a fair and
transparent judicial treatment
action against extradition to USA the
United Nations Special Rapporteur on
torture and other cruel inhumane or
degrading treatment Niels Meltzer
visited Julian Assange in prison on the
9th of May 2019 with a group of medical
doctors they concluded that Assange
showed all symptoms that are typical
consequences of prolonged mental torture
we are deeply alarmed by the UN findings
concerning Assange a state of health and
of the legal proceedings he has been
subjected to in particular by the
Swedish police from 2010 and onwards
that's just 2010 for a decade Assange
was arrested for breach of bail in the
UK an act which is not a crime as he
feared extradition to Sweden for
accusations of rape raised by the
Swedish police Meltzer holds that
Assange a subsequent fear of extradition
to Sweden and then further to the US was
well-founded the UN report argues that
this and the number of other serious
breaches of law may have been carried
out by the authorities during the
process against Assange Sweden has said
Sweden has since it started this ball to
roll under the protection from torture
treaty CIT a responsibility also for the
pain inflicted upon Assange in Belmarsh
and Britain the Swedish prosecutor and
police have refused to respond to claims
presented in a letter of the 12th of
September 2019 not to respond to the UN
report and the serious accusations it
presents is unacceptable it undermines
the authority of the United Nations and
the public is entitled to this
information if respect for judicial
institutions is to be upheld
we the signatories of this appeal find
the report of the United Nations
repertoire on torture and of the UN's an
office on arbitrary detention deeply
alarming we demand the immediate release
of Julian Assange from British prison
and that he be granted asylum in Sweden
or another country of his choice
guaranteed not to be extradited to the
US the present coronavirus threat
aggravates the situation even further
and makes his release even more pressing
did you guys want to jump in at all
before I keep going
I just wanna I want to give this a shut
up before you get to the end of it
because I threw it in the on live chats
for everybody to there is a link at the
bottom of this article that lets you
actually go and sign on to this appeal
yourself on the original signers of it
were JumpShip tin noam chomsky I believe
Julian's mom is on there Eva Jodie and
they're just a bunch of other wonderful
wonderful well-known and high-profile
activists and things like that many
politicians like there's a German
politician that's on there so if you
could please go I believe that set
Julian free is the website for that let
me just double check though it's a.org I
threw it in my chat - yep it's at Julian
free.org so please go and sign that
because that is super important to get
as many signatures on there as we
possibly can no I agree that you want to
wrap up the letter and then we'll
discuss and whatnot yeah sure so the end
of this we further demand that the
Swedish Minister Ministry of Justice
respond to the allegations brought forth
by the said UN authorities and instruct
appropriate Swedish legal action be
taken for a full and transparent
investigation into a possible
disappearance of documents alleged by
the UN report in order to clarify if or
to what extent illegal destruction of
evidence and perversion of the course of
justice has taken place a full and
transparent investigation into the why
the into why the case Assange has been
in to why the case against the signed
has been stretched out over years when
Swedish law sets a strict limit of
months for such proceedings a full and
transparent investigation into the
nature of cooperation between Swedish
and British police with the alleged aim
of conducting extra legal arrest
harassment and detention of Julian
Assange and with the possible aim of
extraditing him to a third country that
Sweden respect the United Nations by
fulfilling its obligations to inter alia
the following international treaties of
which it is a signatory States the
convention
against torture and other cruel inhuman
or degrading treatment or punishment cat
ratified 1986 the International Covenant
on Civil and Political Rights CCP are
ratified in 1971 international law
commissioned the International wrongful
act of a state ALC and I was
we finally demand that Julian Assange be
given a fair treatment in accordance
with principles of basic human rights
and the rule of law and that any
wrongdoings against him brought about by
representatives of the Swedish
authorities be rectified and fully
compensated for in accordance with
Swedish law so that's the end of that
and I in the bottom here to Andrews
point you know some of the other people
who signed on were John Pilger yes John
John shipped and Julian's father Noam
Chomsky NSA whistleblower Tom Drake
German journalist Goethe Wallrath and
former UN assistant secretary general
Dennis holiday holiday and then
everybody watching the vigil tonight as
well every last one of you share this
article around and please share that
link around most specifically for Assad
Julian free org because that is super
important to get people signing onto
that and while your any link sharing
mood we're going to go ahead and put the
GoFundMe up one more time because you
know three weeks in DC is a long time to
- won't be away and yeah it's it's one
of those things where we went into we
went into February knowing it was going
to be a learning experience and we
learned a ton and we can't wait to be
able to roll it out onto the streets of
Washington DC but we definitely need
your help to be able to do that so if
you can please do donate if you can't we
totally get it please share the heck out
of the link and please join us
because it is gonna be a blast
we're in leather we've had for probably
about three or four like behind the
scenes organizer meetings and I'm just
really excited to put out the official
dates and times and all that for when
things are going on because it's going
to be if we can pull it off right it's
going to be super impressive so I hope
that it it's a way that we can build
attention and momentum around this issue
but for this was actually an article
that this next one that Kendra had
recommended out of the medium um so let
me get this pulled up here let me know
when it's up on screen Josh but this is
Assange is hell in the US spice so this
article really breaks down what we've
learned recently about the theft of
documents from Julian out of the
Ecuadorian Embassy the money that got
transferred at all that do you want to
pick this one up Seaver do you want to
Kendra I got it give me just a second
I'm posting a link to our discord in my
chat and by the way it is in the action
document as well I don't guess we missed
a call to actions so this is by Jude
Flemming it was it dropped two days ago
and it says the unimaginable happened to
Julian Assange on April 11th 2019 today
of betrayal when he was abducted by
British police and then transferred to a
high-security prison on behalf of the
United States the Bata breach infraction
was a ruse for the immediate goal
putting him in proxy custody for the US
but it got worse Ecuadorian officials
received a u.s. request for access to
Assange his personal property left in
the Ecuadorian embassy post kidnap then
a judge authorized a judicial request to
go through everything it was an
invitation to pillage his privacy and
legal defense last May 20th to 23rd 2019
Assange is personal
professional legal and medical effects
including cash 27 phones cameras
handwritten notebooks sim and memory
cards routers legal documents digital
storage devices laptops and paper files
and binders the objects were removed by
prosecutors Wilson told ANCA me I'm out
screw that all up and Fabian Chavez in
cooperation with a criminal assistance
request by the u.s. within the
extradition process it was a massive
heist for which Ecuador was handsomely
rewarded items were first transferred to
Quito and placed under the custody of
the judicial police Ecuador allowed the
u.s. to help themselves do Assange his
belongings yet he can't access them I am
not sure where his belongings are now
they could be in Ecuador where the US
examines them or possibly in the u.s.
much of it has likely been uploaded to a
secure cloud for remote access and team
forensics by one estimate the computing
and cellular equipment has a hundred and
ten terabytes with thousands of
encrypted files according to the Evening
Standard quote the search is being
carried out under the authorization of a
judge and following a request for
judicial assistance from the United
States adding that other countries had
also made similar requests if officials
do decide to confiscate any of the
whistleblowers belongings these will be
sent to Ecuador for analysis and then
possibly passed on to those seeking
judicial assistance it has been a year
since Ecuador sneeze diss on his assets
and subsequently gave access to the
United States
his arch adversary the search and
seizure of legal defense manuscripts
cell phones laptops and memory storage
devices is the horror of every
journalist activist researcher or
publishers Assange was robbed even
though his even though it is his stuff
neither he nor his lawyers family or
colleagues can access it by extension
the Assange defense team has been robbed
that is what he meant when he spoke
during an October 21st 2019 case
management hearing quote
this is not equitable I can't research
anything I can't access any of my
writing it's very difficult where I am
in Belmarsh I'm up against a superpower
with unlimited resources
I can't think properly and real quick
here this is we read the indc the first
time the introduction for the book
cypherpunks which is a transcript of one
of the TV shows that Julian had a series
that he did but in that first opening
and we actually have a vigil where we
went through the first chapter of that
book and the prologue of it he
specifically points out how what it
comes down to is that encryption and the
ability to secure information behind a
digital border so to speak is innate
within the universe and it'll come down
to a time when it essentially is drawn
out between the powers of the state
being exercised to perform torture
against Julian and the ability for them
to solve the keys to these encryption
codes and the the words that he uses is
no amount of torture can solve a math
problem or no amount of force can solve
a math problem and I think that that's
what this heist
I hope ultimately shows is that the u.s.
even though they have this immense
physical global power to reach and grab
this man and drag his life down for ten
years still can't cross that barrier of
that encryption wall without him being
the one to allow them to do it
you want to go ahead and move on to the
the contract tracing can't I always say
contract because I feel like these are
paid Pinkertons say a little lower down
in this article if we could scroll down
a bit in this Josh it actually gets into
the possessions like the list of
possessions that they took from Julian
so I just wanted to make sure because
that's about the most important thing to
get out to people for all this well and
I think it's also important just real
quick to remember that you know I mean
they they did all of this for somebody
who supposedly just violated a bail
charge you know I mean and that's that's
a big deal to remember and now he's you
know he is just on remand even in the
eyes of the law he is not you know he
has not been convicted of anything ever
so it's again that you know punishment
by by process and then even making sure
that the process is not in any way going
to be fair to him whatsoever that's it I
just wanted to get that in there for
this specific article so our own Taylor
hoodak is in my chat right now on slow
news day she has question specifically
for you Andrew can Andrew explained the
definition of solidarity and what it
means to him so solidarity is and
everyone's laughing at this points back
to a super old vigil but solidarity is
standing alongside someone in so many
words it is recognizing that they have a
a struggle as well and that it may or
may not in some way be inter related to
yours but still matters in the grand
scale of everyone existing um I like to
add to that and I don't know if there's
a proper word to express it but that
feeling of solidarity put into action
and I don't necessarily know what that
term is so if anyone has any suggestions
for either ideas it's one of those
verbal failings that I have I got a
phrase for it and Reverend Annie
chambers gave it to me and Malcolm X
gave it to her and that phrases we only
get what we organize and take I think
that defines it pretty well I I think
every little hipster out there in
YouTube land should get a nice little
delicate strip tattoo of that
on them and then like go flex in the
mirror and be like oh yeah we only go we
organize and take yes I'll organize and
go take it at least what we're after is
a show of non-violent force or
solidarity if you will in Washington DC
to move a a conversation into a post
partisan realm and that conversation is
like I was saying earlier individual no
matter what your cause is it doesn't get
a chance to proliferate if we don't have
free and open information if we can't it
okay first of all if we can't have
unfettered access to what the truth is
through primary source documentation
first person primary source interviews
then all we have is what we're being
told to think or how to feel about
something by people whose job it is to
obfuscate so I can't stress this enough
if you're someone who is currently
involved in an activist cause on the
front of your sign should be your cause
on the back side of your sign
should be free Julian Assange and you
can feel free to spin that around as
often as you like because you don't get
one without the other I think that's so
true and to your point in solidarity it
reminds me too of like even the minds
coming together when we were all in DC
you know you had some different
political ideas and different things
like that at least I know for me but um
but you know you see people coming
together like to Steve's point and
something more important and so I think
that that's part of what we have to
remember especially in this solidarity
movement is you know you might hear
things depending on what side you're on
that are a little bit you know that
might be like cat claws on a chalkboard
or something but you just you know you
got to let that go
while we concentrate on us being able to
you
fight about it with truthful information
later on you know because right now it's
like we have an alien invasion going on
that we have to stop I mean I'd like to
point out that on today's vigil just to
what you were talking about we had
someone who is in support of a
government ran health care system on the
same panel standing in solidarity with
someone that is running an organization
that is about making sure private health
care still exists so in so many words to
define the organization so ideas like
this like Julian Assange and press
freedom and basic privacy rights and the
right to trial and things like that are
so much more fundamental that it just
builds this great foundation for
everything else to then be placed upon
true and then also you know the First
Amendment you know you don't have any
other civil liberties without that you
have to have that because otherwise you
don't know what's happening with you all
the other ones and you have to it you
have to have the second to ensure that
you get to keep the first and you have
the fourth so that you're not freaking
your what's left of our civil look I
can't I can't stress enough just how
god-awful it is that that Wyden
amendment failed by one vote to make
sure that your web browsing history
isn't accessed whenever the hell the
federal government feels like accessing
it to be used against you it's not that
the federal government wants to send
targeted advertising to you so you buy
their shoots they want to use this
information against you legally against
you politically to [__] your activism
to [__] your organization um I don't
really got I so like but I still don't
want my browser history read that's a
very [__] intimate thing like I like
[__]
it's not yours I said that out loud
didn't I I think I was talking over them
you know so to a point with that - like
as ridiculous as having to argue against
allowing the federal government
unlimited access to your browser history
actually is but for the way that it can
be used beyond just simply targeting
people is collecting people's data about
what they're observing in a more direct
fashion to be able to tailor the
propaganda better and I don't know if
I'm really explaining that well or
simplifying it well but essentially
being able to see what content people
are viewing and then tailoring the
content to make them think a certain way
John Bolton has a super PAC and if you
didn't know that John Bolton has a super
PAC John Bolton has a super PAC and a
few years ago he they put out a document
that basically was an instruction manual
for to do exactly what you're saying how
to best target people to psychologically
manipulate them to get them to vote your
way there there's a whole workup there's
a white paper on it it's one of them
have to go find that link but I will
find that link and all we can show it on
Saturday
yeah industry built around the
regulation of voter thought essentially
and it starts at its core with the
algorithms that exist within social
media companies in the way they actually
allow people's information to be
proliferated which I was always a big
thing that you know Julian Assange was
talking about and especially right
before they you know cut his internet at
the Embassy that they'd had these
advanced algorithms where you wouldn't
even you would you know you would have
been gone it step one even though it
took you five steps to get where they
wanted you to go but that you're gonna
end up there no matter what you know and
that's that's scary thought I had an
absolute legend in independent hip hop
on my show this morning and I asked him
like just a general question about I
think I think it was related to Julian
Assange but he was like look man you got
to understand this isn't the mid-90s
anymore people get big because they sell
out before they make it big because an
algorithm determines their success the
artists ability doesn't determine their
success the fans don't determine their
success they don't know their fans until
the algorithm tells them they need to
like it because it already conforms with
everything that they have co-signed man
you know with with their consent fully
manufactured and that's just a wild way
to look at it and it's true not just
with art but with information and with
politics like I've been you a number of
different candidates for president that
nobody's ever going to get a chance to
vote for because even the Green Party in
the Libertarian Party seem to be doing a
pre selection process but those guys all
have the right to be heard their ideas
all have the right to be discussed but
because algorithmically they get shut
out of the conversation before a real
conversation takes place they're you
know confined to the the dark corners of
the interwebs well and you have you know
this convincing of the public going on
but it's you know it's not in your
interest to hear these these other
stupid candidates you know that's always
been a complaint I've had even with the
presidential debates that we don't have
a third party and they're you know I
mean that's even if you say that that
you know that's nothing for the people
okay well then let them make that let's
let us make that decision you know and I
understand there has to be some process
where you can't have you know like I
can't just be on the presidential debate
because I decided to you know but still
you see what I'm saying
so Juliana talked about the use of
artificial intelligence propaganda I
think that was one of the last
conversations he got to have before he
got cut from actually being able to
speak and communicate and so I just want
to point out to people because he did a
really good job of breaking down the way
money and our current media structure
influences the way people consume
content and I just like to leave people
with the idea of being aware that there
are some people and channels and media
institutions that exists specifically to
heard people into specific narratives
and it applies broadly and sometimes
it's individuals and sometimes it is
institutions but just keep an eye out
for those because it's one of those
things that you can't really tear it
down but at the same time you have to be
intimately aware of when something like
that is occurring and sometimes it's
individual institutions and sometimes
it's individuals who should be
institutionalized to work for the
institutions who are individually doing
what Andrew just said you all talk about
privacy international yeah let's do that
because it really is one of those things
where where I feel like the concept of
contact tracing the the snitch patrols
they're never going away there's going
to be multiple reasons to deploy a
snitch army throughout especially as we
become more and more impossibly offer
Terry
so yeah let's go ahead and and take a
look at that one
I had it up where'd it go so it starts
by going over it's what they call key
findings and privacy international has
done great work they speak out against a
whole lot of things but this in
particular I want to point out because
it's something that's very disconcerting
to me as someone that understands why
privacy exists which is to limit
people's ability to bring down
institutions against other individuals
essentially not allowing people to use
processes punishment and this contact
tracing throughout this entire article
is framed as well we can do it the right
way and I think that the entire framing
of this article is completely I don't
know just overshadowed by the fact that
they're not arguing against contact
tracing they're just arguing against how
to make it okay
well I think that goes to the point of
the you know the echo chamber which are
you know allowed a certain lively debate
within that but what's not on the table
is whether contract tracing is okay in
the first place I can't get this stupid
article little own song useless right
now I'm floundering closing out every
other okay well if anybody has it up
already go ahead and hmm run with it is
there any specific part in here Andrew
that you kind of wanted to go over the
key findings of the privacy
international article okay um so their
key findings guys are contact tracing is
an important emergency healthcare
initiative and is necessarily invasive
coronavirus apps do much more and much
less than manual contact tracing there
are dangerous
tracing initiatives that regular
regularly report on your activities
there are interesting initiatives that
may or may not work these are somewhat
privacy aware and can be either
centralized or decentralized Apple and
Google support decentralized proximity
tracing and privacy and security aware
ways those who build these systems need
to quickly build and in
trust they've been failing in secrecy no
much that's interesting wording
especially when it comes to Apple and
Google Apple and Google support
decentralized proximity tracing and
privacy and security aware way that is
the exact same thing as a politician
supporting Medicare for all it
Pramila jayapal for example who wrote a
medicare-for-all bill introduced it into
Congress last year ostensibly supports
Medicare girl just the other day hopped
on the tweeters and said Americans need
access to affordable health care which
is the exact same thing as saying [__]
you peasant you're not getting your
Medicare for all you're not getting
universal health you're not you're not
we're gonna work on getting you access
to affordable health care I have access
to a Bugatti I cannot afford a Bugatti
but I have access to it you know in the
same way that Google and Apple support
the privacy and security awareness in a
decentralized fashion but will they
implement it oh no oh no they're already
not well and one thing too I was gonna
ask you guys maybe you could confirm
this but I know that I had heard that I
thought that they were just kind of
automatically loading this into the
updates anyhow is that correct or it's
not just they're talking about doing
that well that's may update the contact
tracing app is inker may update and i
think it's important we should try to
get Shawn back on as soon as possible
just to give people some type of
presentation about installing on like
f-droid or something on an iPhone or
things like that just so that way it can
I'm gonna get around it I don't know if
we're allowed to show people how to do
something like that but I feel like we
should and I think Shawn could probably
put something
gather pretty quick to help us out I
feel like if it'll get a 4a in trouble
then we can do it through slow news day
and all get in trouble yeah yeah I
really do you know I mean I'll go ahead
and step up for that one I will in this
privacy international article there's
not one mention of volunteer right they
mentioned the UK multiple times they
talked about their system and how
they're rolling out contact tracing apps
and things like that but not once do
they mention the actual private
intelligence company that is running the
data sets for this and the people and
other organizations and institutions
that have contracts with that company
that would then be able to access those
data sets and I think that that's highly
irresponsible to not mention anything
about Holland here to not mention
anything about the five eyes and 4a
international privacy institution to not
put five eyes and pollen tear on the
front of this Perona virus contact
tracing is beyond irresponsible to put
it to put it like who have you heard
referenced the five eyes outside of like
people who were like personal friends
with Suzy Dawson I mean the honest
that's an honest question like is there
a discussion about the five eyes global
intelligence sharing that we're going on
in another corner of the internet that
I'm unaware of
because like the first time that I heard
it Julian had brought it up yeah it was
a like a 2012 speech maybe he was
already in the embassy it was I mean he
was giving like a good speech at a
conference or something like that and he
mentioned it and it's one of those
things were like if you know great but
like it's not a secret handshake more
people should know what this institution
is in
who they are and what they do and
volunteers involved in the three
different pieces of healthcare
legislation in Australia right now - I
think that will give them control of
three of the five five eyes nations and
there's no alarms being sounded at any
level of the media about that level of
consolidation of information that I'm
aware of no and every single one of
those simulated exercises from dark
winter all the way on to eventual on
crimson contagion all of them all of
them what's make tin to it continuity of
government and a complete shutdown of
the people's internet who prospers
during that transitional continuity of
government period its organizations like
Palantir who not only have the contracts
but they have all of our data they have
all of our information and they've got
direct clients they've got direct
clients who sole purpose of their job is
to target activists organizers and and
people who are trying to take an
individual or collective stand for some
level of corporate responsibility and
because we got to be more we're gonna
start wrapping up here in a little bit
we got a couple minutes but just to kind
of piggyback off of something that Steve
had been talking about the the entire
coronavirus institution now essentially
that's forming that's allowing all of
this crazy stuff to happen a lot of
times you hear the argument from people
when you try to talk to them a lot like
the global power consolidation that's
happening right now with all of these
institutions and they say well they're
not just going to go bankrupt like
they're not just going to close down all
this and shut it down for nothing and a
lot of times they they will because
it's an investment into a larger larger
plan the big players were still allowed
to continue and keep operating
throughout all of this the small
businesses were destroyed but those
larger institutions took a loss because
there's a lot to gain down the road and
there's a lot of money to be made
through the use of intelligence
community data basing contact tracing
and advertising not including the
political torture that can come from it
by selling this information off but I
would like to thank everybody for
joining us tonight for our 46 vigil we
will be back again on Saturday at 1:00
p.m. Eastern Time
my name is Andrew Smith you can find me
on Twitter at Andrews Zigman Zi ji and
und and you can find all of us and this
on Twitter at action underscore the
number for Assange and action for
Assange on YouTube as well and hi
everybody into the chat and thank you to
Josh and Kimber as well and my name is
Kendra Christian and you can find me on
Twitter at Deb's 13 and you can follow
Denver free Assange at dnv free DJ a if
you're seeing me for the first time my
name's Steve Boykin and I do host a show
called slow news day you can find it
here on youtube by typing slow news day
podcast into your search bar I am also
on the rock fendi live and a couple
other platforms occasionally depending
on how much they are Kevin ting me at
the moment
um do you check out the interview I did
with RA the rugged man this morning it's
freaking it's a really good conversation
ray mcgovern
will be on my show this Sunday I'm
really looking forward to that I don't
have a lot booked this week I'm gonna be
on a panel with Nikko house on Thursday
our wonderful tech guy here sleepy josh
is also my tech guy and I'm trying not
to kill him because I tried to the last
few weeks so I'm taking a break from
murdering my tech guys slowly and and
just trying to get out some quality
shows in between big thanks to our guest
tonight
Fiorella is
karoku and norman singleton again thanks
sleepy Josh on the ones and twos mean
panda for the graphics you guys in the
chat we we love you we we do we we do
this because you guys give us all of the
energy in the world forest thank you
very very much
do pass around to GoFundMe link do look
at the action link for the week if you
can donate to the GoFundMe please do
that if you can't again no big deal just
proliferate the link please and we'll
see you saturday good luck to us all